# Min (Mia) Shi

Dallas, TX 75252 | (469) 403-7557 | minmiashi@gmail.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/min-mia-shi/

https://minshimia.github.io

#### **SUMMARY**

Dedicated Political Science Ph.D. candidate, Business Analytics and Data Analytics master's student with four years of experience working with diverse types of data; Equipped with strong skills in data visualization, SQL query, big data, machine learning (ML), and time series model building; Actively seeking Summer 2023 Data Analyst Internship.

#### **EDUCATION**

Ph.D. Candidate in Political Science
2019 The University of Texas at Dallas, Richardson, TX
Master of Science in Social Data Analytics and Research
2021 The University of Texas at Dallas, Richardson, TX
Master of Science in Business Analytics
2022 The University of Texas at Dallas, Richardson, TX

Anticipated May 2024 GPA: 3.936/4.0 Anticipated May 2024 GPA: 3.936/4.0 Anticipated May 2024 GPA: 4.0/4.0

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

**Programming**: Python, R, SQL, Stata, SAS

Tools: Alteryx, Tableau, Jupyter Notebook, Excel Charts, R Shiny

Database & Big Data: MySQL, PostgreSQL, Mango DB, Amazon RDS, Hadoop, Sqoop, Hive, Impala, Pig, Spark

Certificate: Graduate Certificate in Applied Machine Learning at UTD, AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner,

Alteryx Designer Core Certificate

Languages: English, Chinese, Japanese

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

Research Assistant - School of Economic, Political & Policy Sciences at UTD

May 2020 - Present

- Project I: Explored the effects of the 2014-16 Ebola Crisis on WHO-reporting Nations' Systemic Adaptations and 2020-21 COVID-19 Response; Collaborated with my coworkers in generating original data for 245 WHO-reporting nations, conducting statistical analytics, writing reports, and submitting to journals
- Project II: Accomplished data cleaning of 1212 cross-country surveys in Python, utilized t-tests, correlation analysis, fixed effect regression models to perform data analysis in R
- Project III: Utilized time series GARCH models in modeling the effects of U.S.-China trade conflicts on U.S. companies; Presented the findings at 2022 International Society for Data Science and Analytics Conference

## Database Management Intern - Lucion Technology Corp., Ltd., China

July 2017 - August 2017

- Collaborated with IT department manager and used MySQL to manage enterprise users' information, orders of services, billing, and the deployed network devices data, which improved data extraction efficiency by 50%
- Visualized network structures of Lucion Tech. Corp. in Microsoft Visio
- Created over ten BI reports based on analysis of users' structure, competitors, and market trend

### **PROJECTS**

#### Geospatial Truck Fleet Big Data Analytics and Visualization

August 2022 – November 2022

- Used big data Hadoop ecosystem to process geospatial data ingestion, transformation, and database creation
- Performed data exploration and visualization in Tableau by connecting to Hadoop ecosystem server
- Modeled how factors affect the truck driver risk factor, drew a final report and proposed suggestions on how to lower the probability of large trucks accidents

# Payroll Management System Database Design via MySQL

June 2022 - August 2022

- Led a group of five in conducting business requirements analysis and designing a payroll management database with MySQL consisting of 13 tables
- Increased efficiency in extract-transform-load and payroll database management by 100% via stored functions, procedures, and triggers

# COVID-19 Worldwide Cases Synchronous Dashboard using Tableau

December 2021 – January 2022

- Designed a synchronous Tableau dashboard with advanced interactive functions to explore COVID-19 severity
- Utilized Tableau to probe the correlation between factors and the severity of COVID-19 by country

## **AWARDS**